Guide to the Whitney Humanities Center, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records, 1951-1987; Accession 1989-A-026
  - History, The Arts and Letters
    - Comprehensive Exams, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 422)
    - Distinction in the Major, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 423)
    - Syllabi, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 424)
    - HAL 270 Applications, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 425-426)
    - HAL 380 Applications, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 427-428)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 429)
    - Senior Colloquia, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 430)
    - Termination of Program, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 431)
    - Director's Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 432)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 433)
    - Comprehensive Exams, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 434)
    - Course Book Requisitions, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 435)
    - Senior Essays, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 436)
    - Senior Essay Colloquia, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 437)
    - Distinction in the Major, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 438)
    - Kilborne Scholarship, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 439)
    - Junior Seminar, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 440)
    - Syllabi, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 441)
    - Final Examinations, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 442)
    - Director's Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 443)
    - Teaching Assistants, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 444)
    - Syllabi, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 445)
    - Application Forms, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 446)
    - Arts Committee, 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 447)
  - Modern Studies
    - Description, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 448)
    - Syllabi, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 449)
  - Directed Studies
    - Director's Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 450)
    - Course Book Requisitions, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 451)
    - Faculty Information, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 452)
    - Minutes of Student Meetings, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 453)
    - Preparation for Class of 1986, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 454)
    - Francis Riggs Prize, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 455)
    - Writing Tutor, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 456)
    - Classroom Allocation, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 457)
    - Colloquia, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 458)
    - Applications, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 459-461)
    - Waiting List, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 462)
    - Syllabi, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 463-464)
    - Applications, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 465-468)
    - Preparation for the Class of 1984, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 469)
    - Colloquia, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 470)
    - Course Book Requisitions, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 471)
    - Majors List, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 472)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 473)
    - Francis Riggs Prize, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 474)
    - Director's Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 475)
    - Syllabi, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 476-477)
  - Modern Studies
    - Seminars, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 478)
    - Course Book Requisition, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 479)
    - Teaching Assistants, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 480)
    - Director's Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 481)
    - Enrollment, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 482)
    - Syllabi, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 483)
  - Special Programs in the Humanities, Administration
    - Bulletin Information, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 484)
    - Director's Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 485)
    - Special Courses in the Humanities, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 486)
    - Expenses, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 487)
    - Budget Statements, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 488)
    - Governing Board, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 489)
    - Faculty Information, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 490)
    - Mellon Foundation, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 491)
    - Committee on Expository Writing, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 492)
    - Proposed Courses, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 493)
    - Proposal for Renaissance Studies, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 494)
    - Profile, Class of 1985, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 495)
    - Bursary EmploYment, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 496)
    - Review Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 497)
    - Expenses, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 498-499)
    - Bulletin Copy, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 500)
    - Correspondence with Dean H. Lamar, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 501)
    - Faculty Information, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 502)
    - Enrollment Figures, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 503)
    - Budget Statements, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 504)
    - Official Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 505)
    - Report to Dean H. Lamar, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 506)
    - Governing Board, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 507)
    - Sub-Committee Meeting Notes, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 508)
    - Undergraduate Major Statistics, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 509)
    - Report on Program Changes, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 510)
  - Directed Studies
    - Director's Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 511)
    - Classroom Allocation, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 512)
    - Course Book Requisitions, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 513)
    - Faculty Information, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 514)
    - Colloquia, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 515)
    - Preparation for Class of 1985, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 516)
    - Syllabi, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 517-518)
    - Francis Riggs Prize, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 519)
    - Writing Tutor, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 520)
    - Applicants, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 521-525)
  - Modern Studies
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 526)
    - Course Book Requisitions, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 527)
    - Enrollment, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 528)
    - Teaching Assistants, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 529)
    - Syllabi and Examinations, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 530)
  - Scholars of the House
    - Miscellaneous, 1981-1987 (Box 13, Folder 531)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 532)
    - Exam Schedule, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 533)
    - Expenses, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 534)
    - General Information, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 535)
    - Presentations for J. Schori and D. Edelson, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 536)
    - Prospective Scholars, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 537)
    - Lists of Scholars, 1977-1985 (Box 13, Folder 541)
    - Director's Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 542)
    - Bulletin Copy, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 545)
    - Scholar List, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 546)
    - Bulletin Copy, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 547)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 548)
    - Examination Schedules, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 549)
    - Expense Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 550)
    - General Information, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 551)
    - Prospective Scholars, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 552)
    - Presentations, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 558)
    - Bulletin Copy, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 559)
    - Scholar List, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 560)
    - Bulletin Copy, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 561)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 562)
    - Expenses, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 563-564)
    - Presentations, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 656-566)
    - Exam Schedule, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 567)
    - Production Costs, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 568)
    - General Information, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 569)
    - Prospective Scholars, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 570)
    - Rejected Applications, 1982~1983 (Box 13, Folder 571)
    - Review of the Major, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 572)
    - Scholars List, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 573)
    - Bulletin Copy, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 574)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 575)
    - Project Evaluations, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 576)
    - Budget Information, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 577-578)
    - General Information, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 579)
    - Prospective Scholars, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 580)
    - Recommendations, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 581)
- Records relating to special undergraduate programs, circa 1970-1981; Accession 1989-A-035
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2017.
  - Richard McNeil, The Family in the Utopia of Saint Thomas More, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kimberly Benston, This Busy Trade of Life: A Study of John Webster's Drama, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sheila Steiner, Punning in John Donne's Christian Rhetoric: Its Background And Its Aims, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Douglas SaJ.V(;Den, Changing Perceptions of Madness in the Eighteenth Century, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - John Schmidt, Knowledge of Self and Knowledge John Schmidt of History in the Works of Augustine and Hegel: The Conflict and Confluence of Mind and Time, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hans Baldauf, A Place to Hide in:Place,Space, and the Philosophy of Private Property in Land:The Relevence of Hannah Arendt's View, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tony De La Rosa, The IbJitical Ideology of John Knox, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Claire Zion, The Urban Aesthetic: Paris in the Works of Baudelaire,Manet, and Zola, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Douglas Hersh, That We May Do Without, Within: "Romanticism, "Mysticism, "and "History", 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Susan Launi, Questions of Self-Presentation: Stendhal, Courbet, Chateaubriand, Ingres, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Richard Johnson, Sweet Cuckold Airs We Sing, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Linda Cataldo, The Musical Practices of the French Revolution and Their Influences on Beethoven, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Mary Anne Case, The Feminist Writings of Marie Le Jars De Gournay, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sarah Lessels, The Mirror and the Phoenix: Time, History and Progress in the Rainbow, In One Hundred Years of Solitude, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Aaron Detsky, Striking No Chords That Lead Elsewhere: Johannes Vermeer and Dutch Seventeenth Century Culture, 1979 February (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - James Rosenzweig, Turners: Chaos and Eros in Landscape, 1972 May (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Robert Collins, From Shakespeare to the Soft Scarlatti Opera's Impact on the Adaptations of the 17th and 18th Centuries, 1972 May (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Marion Belew,Jr., Truth, Society, And Change in Coleridge, Cobbett, and Mill, 1972 May (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Michael Lonergan, "Superfluous and Impertinent Michael Lonergan Business" The Periodical Reviews of The Lyrical Ballads Childe Harold's Pilgrimage Endymion, 1976 April (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Nicholas Asher, In Pursuit of the Singular Cusanus' Theory of Individuation, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - David Cohn, An Introduction to the Role of David Cohn Tradition in the Music of George Rochberg, 1976 April (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Michael Cadden, A Man and His Masks: The Aesthetic Flight of Oscar Wilde (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Richard Fuchs, The Politics of Social Welfare: The Coming of National Health Service in England (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Eric Moore, Protestant Pessimism: A study of the relationship between the theology and the sociology of Jacques Ellul, 1971 May (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Vincent Teahan, The Condition of England, 26024 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Robert Bowen,Jr, The Worship of Venus And The Ferrarese Mythologies: Titan's Attitude Toward the Antique, 26420 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Philip Kunsberg, Jean-Paul Sartre's Ontology of Consciousness: A Look at the Stuff Which Reality is Made of, 26420 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Jane Maienschein, Helmholtz's "Conservation of Force": Physics or Physiology?, 26420 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Holley Russell, Experiments In Satire: The Advice-To-A-Painter Poems, 26420 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Judith Sizer, Three Revolutions: William Wordsworth, William Blake, and France, 1789-1794, 29646 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - John DeBellis, Kierkegaards's Concept of Selfhood, 28946 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Jeanne Weinberg, Telling Truths Obliquely: Robert Browning's Theory of Art, 28915 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - John Danforth, The Contribution of the Rearguard Dugald Stewart's Common Sense Synthesis of the Scottish Enlightenment, 28915 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Sarai Ribicoff, Living the Past:Thomas Carlyle, Walter Scott, and John Ruskin, 28915 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Sherry Dominick, Satire and Misanthropy in English Literature: 1660' s-1770-' s, 1978 March (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Barbara Frank, Moses Mendelssohn: Jewish Metaphysician of the German Enlightenment, 1977 April (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - James Delphey, An Inquiry Into the Nature of Philosophizing, 1977 April (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - James Arden, G.ardinal Newman's Theory of Belief (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Priscilla Ingersoll, Dr. Price and the Reform Agitation in Britain, 1760-1780, 27851 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - L. Greenfield, Jr, The Language of Reason: Style in Descartes, 1980 March (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - John Taber, Issac Newton And Eighteenth Century Poetry Design Versus Imagination (Box 2, Folder 40a)
  - Victoria Kiechel, The Relation and Irrelation of Text and Image in British Art, 1550-1850: An Exploratory Groundwork, 1977 April (Box 2, Folder 40b)
  - Faith Young, Inns and Theatre in Don Quixote and Tom Jones, 1977 April (Box 2, Folder 40c)
  - Marc Redfield, Charles Dickens: Beginning and the Problematics of Realism, 1980 March (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - HAL Thomas Aquinas Reading, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - HAL Comprehensive Examinations Texts of Paper I, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - HAL Comprehensive Examinations Texts of Paper III, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - HAL Senior Essay Readers, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - HAL Comprehensive Examination Preparation, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Theatre Studies Essay - "SLYFOX" Adapted from "VOLPONE" by Larry GelBart, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Undergraduate Drama At Yale by Terri Elaine Jones, 1976 October (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Changes in the Structure of the New Major (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - HAL Correspondence(Rice-DUS) (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Kilborne Scholarship (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - HAL End-of-Year Wrap-up for Seniors (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - HAL Final Exams (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - HAL History Exam - Used as an equivalent of History 201-202 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - HAL 1977-78 Majors List (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - HAL Search Committee - April, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Second Semester Applicants to Courses in HAL, April,1978 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - HAL Syllabus Committee on Revision (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - DS Applicants accepted for 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Late DS Applicants for 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Directed Studies Applications for 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Colloquium Information (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Directed Studies Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - DS - Evaluations for 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Directed Studies Exams (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Faculty Departmental Credits (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Information Sheets on Certain DS Applicants (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - E. Francis Piggs Memorial Prize (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Second Semester Applicants to DS Courses, 1978 Spring (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Senior Essay Prize Nominations (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Directed Studies Material (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Statistics on DS Students (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Directed Studies Syllabi (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - HAL Comprehensive Examinations Texts of Paper II (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Senior Prospectus (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - HAL Syllabi (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - HAL 160 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - HAL 270 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - HAL 270 Applicants for 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - HAL 380 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - HAL 380 Applicants (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - HAL 489 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - HAL Distinction in the Major (Guidelines) HAL 489 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - HAL Senior Essay Colloquium (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Board Meetings (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Budget 1977-78: Ongoing Costs, Daily Expenditures, Receipts (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Bulletin Material for 77-78 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Correspondence Official (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Faculty List (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - HAL Senior Essay List for Lewis P. Curtis Fund (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - General Appropriations Sheets 77-78 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Personnel Profiles 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Schedule of Classes 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Faculty 1976-1977: Departmental Credits (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Syllabi 1976-77 (Fall) (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - D.S. Student Evaluation 77-78 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Syllabi 1976-1977 (Spring) (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Directed Studies Applicants 77-78 (Box 3, Folder 108)